A Guide to the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation records, Administrative Functions, RG 4 FA1798
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Communications, 1943-2017; 2; 9.78 Cubic Feet 28 containers
  - Biographical Files, 1943-2017; 2.2; 2.09 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes and 1 half document box
    - Biographical Files - Officers and Staff, 1964-2017; 2.2.3
      - Linzer, Lindsay, 2015 October 26-2017 April 6 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        Knight File Number - 5793
        Staff memo announcing the hiring of Lindsay Linzer as Grants Administration Officer. Also, photos of the birth of Zach Linzer on December 24, 2016 and brother Noah. Also included is a memo on her leaving KF for her new role as Director of Grants Administration at the Miami Foundation.
      - Locker, Katy, 2013 August (Box 4, Folder 28)
        Knight File Number - 5370
        News release announcing the appointment of Katy Locker as Program Director for Detroit.
      - Lopez, Javiel, 2014 April 11 (Box 4, Folder 29)
        Knight File Number - 5315
        Email announcing the resignation of Javiel Lopez, Director of Human Resources.
      - Lyons, Adele C., 2007 August 29 (Box 4, Folder 30)
        Knight File Number - 4150
        Editorial on rebuilding efforts after Hurricane Katrine by Adele Lyons, Program Director for Biloxi.
      - Maidenburg, Ben, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
        Knight File Number - 245
        Akron Beacon Journal articles re: Knight Foundation Secretary and President, 1976-77. Also includes some notes from Ben to C.C. Gibson and to/from Ben's family following his sudden death in 1986.
      - Maidenberg, Michael, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        Knight File Number - 3292
        Biographical information on Mike Maidenberg, Vice-President and Chief Program Officer.
      - Maness, Michael, 2012 February 8-2014 August 11 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        Knight File Number - 4978
        Michael Maness, VP of Journalism and Media Innovation, is on the team of the KF-funded Public Media Accelerator project to seek mission-driven media entrepreneurs. Also included is the announcement by Alberto Ibarguen that Maness would leave KF after the September board meeting but remain in a consulting capacity.
      - Martinez, Jorge (George), 2000 September 27 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        Knight File Number - 3826
        Article re: "Knight Foundation Reaches Out While Keeping In Touch with Windows 2000" which mentions Knight Foundation's work and quotes George Martinez, KF Director of Information Systems.
      - Martinez, Juan, 2010 January 29 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        Knight File Number - 4681
        Juan Martinez, VP, CFO & Treasurer, named Nonprofit CFO of the Year by the South Florida Business Journal. Includes memo from Alberto Ibarguen, announcing the honor, and a copy of the article of the award.
      - McManus, Josh, 2014 July 2-2015 January 30 (Box 4, Folder 36)
        Knight File Number - 5369
        Welcome email and press release for Josh McManus, Akron Program Officer, provides biographical details. Also included are Q&A with Carol Coletta and an article by Betty Lin-Fisher on Ohio.com. McManus resigned, effective the end of January. Kyle Kutuchief was named Knight interim program director for Akron. Also included is a memo from Alberto Ibarguen to KF staff about the personnel changes for Akron.
      - McPhee, Penelope, 1997 February 4 (Box 4, Folder 37)
        Knight File Number - 1521
        Release noting Ms. McPhee's appointment as Vice President and Chief Program Officer. Ms. McPhee, initiated the Arts & Culture Program when she was hired in 1990 as its director. Also included are mentions of her appointment in several newspapers and magazines; and several versions of her biographical sketch.
      - Meyer, Larry (Bud), 1995 October 30-2009 January 22 (Box 4, Folder 38)
        Knight File Number - 2804
        Memo from Creed Black to staff on the appointment of Larry Meyer; newspaper editorial written by Meyer re: challenge for foundations; congratulatory letter from Alvah Chapman re: Meyer's appointment as a VP of the foundation onn March 12, 2002; 2008 news release announcing Meyer's transitional position change to senior communications officer and medical leave as of 10/1/08 and retirement as of 2/3/2009 and 2009 news release announcing his retirement.
      - Miller, Elizabeth R., 2011 (Box 4, Folder 39)
        Knight File Number - 5316
        Web biographical sketch for Elizabeth R. Miller, Communications Associate.
      - Morales, Elsie, 2016-2017 (Box 4, Folder 40)
        Knight File Number - 5727
        Welcome and biographical sketch for Elsie Morales, who joined the Communications department as a digital communications officer in September, 2016. Also included is a staff memo announcing her new role as Director of Marketing and Digital Communications with YoungArts Miami.
      - Morgan, Patrick, 2015 December 10-2016 March 3 (Box 4, Folder 41)
        Knight File Number - 5620
        Announcement of hiring of Patrick Morgan as program director for Philadelphia. He begins work at KF on January 4, 2016. Also included is an announcement, with picture, of the arrival of his daughter, Abigail Jean Morgan in March 2016.
      - Neal, Vivian Celeste, 2008 October-2012 September 13 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 4388
        Inside Business,the magazine for business professionals in Northeast Ohio, features on their cover, "Athena Award Finalists" which included in 2008, KF program director Vivian Celeste Neal. Includes award program, biographical sketch and photos. Also included is a news release announcing the retirement of Neal, effective February 26, 2010 and a letter from Neal to Alberto Ibarguen re: her visit to the MLK Memorial in Washington, DC and a picture of her pointing to KF on the memorial as benefactors.
      - Nessa, Shazna, 2017 February 14 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 5794
        Staff memo announcing the resignation of Shazna Nessa.
      - Nessa, Shazna, 2017 February 14-28 (Box 5)
        Knight File Number - 5792
        Email from Jennifer Preston announcing the resignation of Shazna Nessa as of February 28th, 2017.
      - Neuhart, Phyllis, 2004 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 2809
        Luncheon program for lunch honoring the retirement of Phyllis Neuhart.
      - Newkirk, Christa, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 5728
        Welcome and biographical sketch for Christa Newkirk, who joined the Community and National Initiatives program as a program associate in Charlotte in June 2016.
      - Newton, Eric, 2001-2015 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 3827
        News Release re: Eric Newton Joins Knight Foundation as Director of Journalism Initiatives (undated) and resume, dated January 2001; signed and notarized copy of Board of Trustee naming Newton Vice President for Journalism and two copies of an article, written by Newton, appearing in The Chronicle of Philanthropy, July 22, 2012, re: "For Foundations, Clearer Writing Means Wiser Grant Making". Alberto announced Eric's stepping down as special assistant to consultant so that he could assume a leadership role at the Cronkite School of Journalism, Arizona State University. Words to the song, written by Newton, "Get Your Kicks with Knight's 26", first sung at Penny McPhee's Farewell party.
      - Ocon, Julio, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 5729
        Biographical sketch for Julio Ocon, who became director of finance in May, 2016. Also included is a picture of Julio and his family at KF family day at Marlins Park.
      - Oener, Christina, 2015-2017 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 5730
        Memo and biographical sketch for Christina Oener, who was hired as receptionist in June 2015, promoted to IT/Finance assistant in 2016 and joined the Finance Department as Accounts Payable clerk in 2017. Also included is an invitation to a staff baby shower in her and Lilly Weinberg's honor.
      - de Onis, Alejandro, 2014 December 3-2016 March 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 5366
        Staff memo announcing hiring of Alejandro de Onis as the director of digital strategy. He replaces Eric Schoenborn. His title was changed to Director/Digital Strategy and Design on March 1, 2016.
      - Pate, J. Michael, 2008 March-May (Box 5, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 4538
        News article (Spring 2008 issue) re: COCA [Council on Culture & Arts] Notes re: KF grant. Mike Pate is pictured at the awards ceremony.
      - Patel, Mayur, 2009 February 9-2011 March 15 (Box 5, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 4450
        News Release re: Mayur Patel joins Knight Foundation as director of strategic assessment and impact. Announcement that Mayur was elected vice president/strategy and assessment.
      - Patterson, Susan, 2009 April 22-2016 February 10 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 4530
        News item re: Susan Patterson received the lifetime achievement award at the Hornets Nest Girl Scout Council's 4th annual Women of Distinction Award luncheon. Picture at the awards ceremony shows Patterson with her mother. Also included is a photo of a Reserved Parking sign for Susan with a funny note from Alberto Ibarguen and a staff memo from Alberto re: announcement of Patterson's retirement, effective 12/31/2015 and images from her retirement party (several guests are wearing crazy wigs in honor of Susan's eclectic hair color choices). Also included is a Charlotte Observe news article, "Dinwiddie, Patterson are Women of the Year" in Charlotte.
      - de la Pena, Benjamin, 2013 October-2016 December (Box 5, Folder 12)
        Knight File Number - 5752
        Biographical sketch of Benjamin (Benjie) de la Pena, who was hired in October 2013 as director of community and national strategy. He resigned in December 2016.
      - Preston, Jennifer, 2014 September 8-October 8 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        Knight File Number - 5456
        News release, news articles and staff emails announcing the hiring of Jennifer Preston as the VP of Journalism, replacing Michael Maness. The reorganization of the JMI department is also mentioned. Included is a Board of Trustees resolution, dated September 8, 2014, naming Jennifer Preston as a vice-president of Journalism.
      - Rogers, Victoria, 2015 March 8 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        Knight File Number - 5587
        News release re: appointment of Victoria Rogers as Vice President of Arts, replacing Dennis Scholl.
      - Ross, Lynn, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 15)
        Knight File Number - 5731
        News release announcing the hiring of Lynn Ross as vice president for community and national initiatives.
      - Schoenborn, Eric, 2012 April 6-2014 December 30 (Box 5, Folder 16)
        Knight File Number - 4990
        Miami Herald story of an art project commissioned by The Bass Museum of Art which features a collaborative effort by Eric Shoenborn, KF communications associate, and artist Jillian Mayer; KF staff bio page; and farewell letter from Eric to his KF colleagues.
      - Scholl, Dennis, 2009 April 22-2015 October 13 (Box 5, Folder 17)
        Knight File Number - 4528
        News Release re: Dennis Scholl joins KF as Miami program director. Also included is a release re: promotion of Scholl to vice president/arts; an editorial written by Scholl re: Detroit's cultural scene and an article in Barrister, the Alumni Magazine for the University of Miami School of Law (Fall 2009) about Dennis. Also included is an email from Alberto announcing Dennis' leaving KF and an updated bio sketch.
      - Sherry, Andrew, 2012 December 12 (Box 5, Folder 18)
        Knight File Number - 4991
        Board of Trustees resolution naming Andrew Sherry Vice President/Communications.
      - Sotsky, Jonathan, 2010 November-2017 March 21 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        Knight File Number - 5883
        Staff biography of Jonathan Sotsky, Director of Strategy and Assessment. Also included is a birth announcement for his daughter, Aviva.
      - Spaniolo, James, 1989-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
        Knight File Number - 246
        Biographical sketch and newspaper articles re: Vice President and Chief Program Officer, 1989-1996.
      - Suero, Priscilla, 2016 March 24 (Box 5, Folder 21)
        Knight File Number - 5755
        Staff memo announcing the promotion of Priscilla Suero to program administration coordinator, CNI. Priscilla joined KF in 2012.
      - Talen, Polly M., 2005 December 23-2015 April 14 (Box 5, Folder 22)
        Knight File Number - 4537
        News article re: Deborah Talen being named 2005 Person of the Year by Minnesota's GLBT Magazine. Deborah is Polly's partner; Polly is mentioned in the article and pictured on the cover with Deborah and their children. Also included is a press release on the Grand Opening for the Green Line (rapid transit line linking Minneapolis and St. Paul). Polly serves as co-chair of the Funders Collaborative, which is planning and raising funds for the opening weekend in June. Also included is an email from Polly announcing her leaving Knight and an updated biographical sketch.
      - Thomas, Charles, 2016 January 25 (Box 5, Folder 23)
        Knight File Number - 5636
        Staff memo welcoming Charles Thomas, Program Director for Charlotte, effective February 22, 2016. He replaces long-time director, Susan Patterson, who retired in 2015.
      - Thomas, Jennifer, 2014 February 4 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        Knight File Number - 5294
        Email from Jennifer Thomas, Akron Program Director, announcing her exit from KF.
      - Thompson, Amanda, 2015 August 13 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        Knight File Number - 5554
        Staff announcement of the hiring of two Arts team members: Amanda Thompson as an arts program officer and Jessica Miller as executive assistant.
      - Thorman, Damian, 2009 April 22-2013 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        Knight File Number - 4529
        News item re: Damian elected vice-chair of the National Fund for Workforce Solutions and updated bio sketch.
      - Thurman, Bronlynn, 2016 April 26 (Box 5, Folder 27)
        Knight File Number - 5756
        Staff announcement of the hiring of Bronlynn Thurman as Program Associate for Akron.
      - Valiente, Tanya, 2015 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 28)
        Knight File Number - 5553
        Staff announcement of the hiring of Tanya Valiente, executive assistant on the Communications team.
      - Weinberg, Lilly, 2015 April 23 (Box 5, Folder 29)
        Knight File Number - 5588
        Staff memo regarding the promotion of Lilly Weinberg from Special Assistant to director for community foundations. Weinberg replaces Bahia Ramos, who moved to the Arts Department.
      - Winston, Jai, 2016 (Box 5, Folder 30)
        Knight File Number - 5732
        News release and staff memo announcing the hiring of Jai Winston as program director in St. Paul, MN.
      - Wirz, Benoit [Ben], 2010-2015 December (Box 5, Folder 31)
        Knight File Number - 5618
        Bio sketch of Ben Wirz, director of Venture Investments and an email announcing the birth of his second child.
      - Zenni, Nina, 2015 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 32)
        Knight File Number - 5591
        Staff memo regarding the promotion of Nina Zenni to Media Innovation Associate.
    - Biographical Files - Trustees, 1950-2017; 2.2.4
      - Alvarez, Cesar L., 2000-2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Knight File Number - 2782
        News release announcing Cesar Alvarez's election to the KF Board of Trustees; biographical sketches and news release announcing Alvarez being named lawyer of the year by the Hispanic National Bar Association.
      - Austen, Christopher M., 2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
        Knight File Number - 5318
        Web biographical sketch for Christopher Austen, who was elected to the board of trustees to replace Marjorie Knight Crane, who retired. Christopher is the son of W. Gerald Austen.
      - Austen, Dr. W. Gerald, 1996-2010 (Box 1, Folder 3)
        Knight File Number - 1522
        Releases noting Dr. Austen's election to Vice-Chair and later Chairman of the Board of Trustees (succeeding Lee Hills). Dr. Austen has served on the KF Board since 1987 and was elected vice chairman in 1991. Also included is an Akron Beacon Journal article, published June 15, 2000 re: Austen's family ties to Akron and his work with the Knight Foundation; a curriculum vitae and biographical sketch; several articles on Austen's career; and several items commemorating his service to the Knight Foundation, including several brochures distributed at a dinner in his honor, the program for the dinner and an editorial in the Akron Beacon Journal applauding the naming of the Austen BioInnovation Institute and the program from the Board of Trustees dinner honoring Austen on his retirement.
      - Baker, Leslie M. "Bud", Jr., 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
        Knight File Number - 2787
        News release announcing Bud Baker's election to the KF Board of Trustees. He later resigned in 2005.
      - Baron, Marty, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 5)
        Knight File Number - 5724
        News release re: election of Martin (Marty) Baron, executive editor of the Washington Post, as a trustee.
      - Batten, James K., 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
        Knight File Number - 257
        Biographical sketch, articles and obituaries of Knight Foundation Trustee, 1987-1995.
      - Bell-Rose, Stephanie, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
        Knight File Number - 4957
        News release announcing Stephanie Bell-Rose's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation.
      - Borges, Francisco, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
        Knight File Number - 4958
        News release announcing Francisco (Frank) Borges's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation.
      - Briggs, Robert W. "Rob", 2002 June 24-2014 August 29 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Knight File Number - 2786
        Nominating committee report and KF news release on Rob Brigg's election to the KF Board of Trustees. Also included are two press clippings on Briggs' chairing of the Fund for Our Economic Future in Northeast Ohio and news item re: Briggs' receiving the 2009 Sir Thomas More Award from the Catholic Diocese and St. Bernard Church in Akron, OH. Also included is a Wall Street Journal article featuring Briggs and his wife, Alyssa Lenhoff, who recently moved into a downtown Cleveland condo. The article concerns the revitalization of the city.
      - Clark, Charles E., 2006 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Knight File Number - 3835
        Obituary from The Miami Herald for former KF treasurer and trustee, Charles E. Clark (trustee 1969-1991). Mr. Clark died in Miami on September 5, 2006.
      - Coleman, Mary Sue, 2005-2011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Knight File Number - 3020
        Information on Mary Sue Coleman as a "Public University President[s] With the Highest Compensation, 2004-5" in The Chronicle of Higher Education; Q/A with Coleman in Michigan Alumnus magazine, Winter 2005.
      - Considine, William H., 2011 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Knight File Number - 4960
        News release announcing William Considine's election to the BOT, Knight Foundation; blog post re: Considine receiving the Polsky Humanitarian Award.
      - Conway, Jill Ker, 1991-2004 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Knight File Number - 2208
        Release noting Dr. Conway's election as a Knight Foundation trustee; biographical sketches; curriculum vitae; a Lear's magazine interview; news release re: appointment to the board of The Enterprise Foundation; several articles re: book reviews; announcement of death of husband, John Conway; and website profile on the ExxonMobil Masterpiece Theatre presentation of "The Road from Coorain", a dramatization of Conway's memoir. Also included is a program, certificate of commendation, and remarks by Jerry Austen in celebration of Conway's retirement from the KF board.
      - Crane, Marjorie Knight, 1994-2013 (Box 1, Folder 14)
        Knight File Number - 1524
        Release noting Ms. Crane election to the Board of Trustees. Ms. Crane is the daughter of James L. Knight. Also included is a resume and Miami Herald article on her election. Ms. Crane announced her retirement from the KF board, effective with the March 2014 meeting. She wrote an article for Chronicle of Philanthropy re: John S. and James L. Knight and her own giving to Queens University in Charlotte, NC, where she resides. Also included is Knight family genealogical information, some going back many generations and memo and pictures re: dedication of Knight-Crane Hall, home of the James L. Knight School of Communications at Queens University.
      - Crutchfield, Jim, 2004 June 18-2016 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
        Knight File Number - 5228
        Information on Jim Crutchfield, former Akron Beacon Journal publisher, contains the press release of his election to the KF BOT, a Q & A interview re: his appointment to the ABJ and biographical information. Also included is a biographical sketch and a photo of his retirement dinner, where he was joined by Belinda Lawrence, Eric Newton, Terese Coudreaut, and George Martinez.
      - Grogan, Paul S., 2000-2012 (Box 1, Folder 16)
        Knight File Number - 2783
        News release announcing Paul Grogan's election to the KF Board of Trustees in 2000. Also includes biographical sketches and news articles.
      - Harris, Jay T., 1994-1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
        Knight File Number - 1525
        Biographical materials on Jay T. Harris, who joined the Knight Foundation Journalism Advisory Committee in 1989 and served as its chairman for two years before joining the Board as the designated Knight-Ridder publisher in 1994. He served for five years. Materials include comments by W. Gerald Austen in tribute for Harris' service, biographical sketches, a resume, several news releases, and a clipping.
      - Heffern, Gordon E., 1980-2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
        Knight File Number - 2653
        Notices re: Gordon Heffern's election to chairman and chief executive officer of the Cleveland-based Society Corp., 1983; two biographical sketches, 1992, 1999; obituaries on the death of his wife, Neva; articles on his presidency of the Akron Community Foundation; and a resolution and remarks delivered by Gerald Austen at Gordon's retirement dinner, March 2004.
      - Hills, Lee, 1960-2000 (Box 1, Folder 19-24)
        Knight File Number - 1497
        Profiles, articles and clippings, and press releases describing Lee Hills career as a trustee, vice chairman and chairman of Knight Foundation, 1960-1998. Includes recollections of Lee Hills by Janet Reno (4/14/1994, ASNE convention); "comments regarding Lee Hills" by Jerry Austen at a Knight Foundation dinner honoring Lee at his retirement as Foundation chairman in 1996; and a profile by Alf Pratte. Two files relate to Mr. Hills's death (on 2/3/2000) and funeral. Another file contains background on the University of Missouri-Coulmbia School of Journalism's Lee Hills Hall (funded in part by a KF challenge grant as a way to honor Mr. Hills) and the Lee Hills Chair in Free-Press Studies, and the "Tina Hills Award for Service to the Community." (six folders)
      - Hills, Lee, 1995 April 18 (Box 1, Folder 25)
        Knight File Number - 2409
        Transcription of a taped interview with Lee Hills and Tina Hills by Michael Clapp, University of Missouri Journalism School for the CD-rom in connection with the dedication of Lee Hills Hall, Columbia, Missouri. The interview touches on Hills' childhood and education, his love of journalism, his career, his marriage and partnership with Tina Hills, the Knight brothers, and the Knight Foundation.
      - Hughes, Chris, 2009-2012 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        Knight File Number - 4953